[Music]
it's just a quick film to let you know
that we're about to run our online
course again
which is a course designed to teach some
of the skills that we talk about a lot
on the channel
with amazing guest faculty including
daniel schmacktenberger
diane musher hamilton john viveki doshin
roshi
so we've designed the course to move
from inner to outer
and what that means in practice is that
we spend time developing
skills centered around sovereignty so
our ability to stay connected to ourself
to not be hijacked by the information
around us to stay
aware of our environment and then we use
those skills to start making sense of
what's around us more effectively and we
introduce a lot of different tools and a
lot of different
frameworks and models to help us really
understand what the hell is going on
so yeah we've really sifted through all
of the best practices all the best
techniques
what some people on the channel have
called psycho technologies
to help us make sense of the world and
we've chosen the guest faculty
because of their lifetime experience
making use of these techniques
people like daniel schmacktenberger
we're making more and more consequential
choices
with worse and worse making to inform
those choices
which is kind of running increasingly
fast
through the woods increasingly blind i
think many of
the people that you've had on rebel
wisdom have been in a deep inquiry
around how do we actually fix our own
sense making
and then we also have john verveicky who
is a cognitive scientist at the
university of toronto and created the
the very well-regarded awakening from
the meaning crisis series on youtube and
john's session is all about wisdom
what wisdom is how we cultivate it and
how we see through our cognitive biases
to
perceive reality more clearly what is
self-deception what are higher states of
consciousness what is enlightenment what
is wisdom
what's our best cognitive scientific
answer of that and then can we
use that to create what i call
psychotechnologies
and communities and ecologies of them
that can
give us back the cultivation of wisdom
and self-transcendence and
also connect us up to a world view
that valorizes homes legitimates and
makes sense
of that set of practices then we have
diane muscho hamilton who brings
together these amazing skills of being a
zen master
and also a trained mediator what we need
to be doing
is helping people calibrate and move
together
highly coherently and then really
experience
difference as it arises on an embodied
level within the interaction
notice when it flips into threat and try
to calibrate difference and teach people
how to be
indifference because that's where
emergence is more likely to to really
make itself
to really come forward is through this
collision of difference that's what
happens
and we have another zen master doshin
roshi and doshin session is all about
the shadow which is an essential concept
in
our own personal development but also in
how we perceive the world around us and
the effect it has
so his session is always very popular
and here's a clip of him
discussing what the shadow is we have to
have
collective ways of dealing with this
collective shadow
and we've developed some some collective
shadow work some group shadow work where
we
we really talk about these shadows
and we work on them and we help people
become conscious of them so this is the
third time we've run the course
and we've improved it each time and the
feedback just keeps getting better and
better
this is about an ecology of practices
what rebel wisdom does very well
of exposing us to the sages of the day
right
of encountering new material of new
perspectives and things like that
and then learning meditative practices
of being able to look at yourself
and look at these ideas and thank you so
much for those kinds of opportunities
because i don't think there are a lot of
us out here
who understand what this transformative
process is that we're undergoing and the
more that we can understand and
appreciate it and practice it the easier
it will be to anchor it individually
collectively
and organically as a groundswell
movement that changes the course of
human
history human future potential
so thank you so as we said before this
is the third time we're running this
course and we've been improving it every
time
and it's really grown into more than the
sum of its parts so
i also like to think of it as kind of a
process as well
as a course as a really thought
out narrative structure from beginning
to end and as we mentioned it moves from
sort of internal skill sets
then into looking at the world around us
and
that is also supported by the pods so
throughout the course everyone works in
pods of three different people
and they meet once a week and as well as
that we have one live call with one of
the faculty or with rebelism once a week
and on top of that as well there's a
really well thought out really detailed
workbook which has a lot of
self-directed
exercises people can do in their own
time if they choose to so the first two
times we ran the course it sold out
pretty quickly and we expect this one to
sell out as well
so if you're interested click the link
below
and also there's an email address for
any queries that's going to come up on
screen now
so thank you for watching and we hope to
see you soon